Good morning. On this day,
July 1st, 2014. At this hour, 0600.
We are at the very first airport in the world...
The CW-7, which despite being the topic of
so much controversy over the past 7 years,
has continued development.
Protests from environmental groups and
a number of developing countries continue...
It has been claimed that CW-7
is the answer to global warming.
And we are witnessing it!
...world leaders, who argue that
global warming can no longer be ignored.
Today, 79 countries will begin dispersing CW-7
into the upper layers of the atmosphere.
...spray out into the upper layers of
the atmosphere and
surprisingly bring down average
global temperatures to the finest levels.
It is just a day away that
our long time crisis of global warming...
According to scientists, the artificial cooling
substance CW-7 will succeed
in bringing average global temperatures
down to manageable levels,
as a revolutionary solution to
mankind's warming of the planet.
Head check!
Alright. Get in line.
Everybody sit down.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Keep going.
Go on.
Hey you. Sit down!
Curtis, sit down.
Sit down!
I said sit down!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Counting.
Can't you sit and count?
You wanna get shot? You're crazy.
Shut up, Edgar. I'm thinking.
Are there any experienced violinists here?
Raise your hands!
Violinist!
Stand up, come forward.
Food! Come and get it.
Violinists? They're having a laugh?
Those bastards in the Front Section,
think they own us.
Eating steak dinners and listening to
string quartets and that.
We'll be different when we get there.
I want steak.
Excuse me sir!
My wife and I played violin
in the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
I was first chair.
Can you still play?
Of course. You never forget.
Show me your hands.
You. Follow me.
Leave your belongings, we just need your hands.
Not both?
Yes. Both hands.
My wife, Doris, plays beautifully.
Better than me even.
They just need one person.
Then I won't go.
Doris, Doris.
Sit down everyone.
- Sit down, Edgar.
- They can't just...
Sit down.
Fucking bastards.
Now isn't the time.
Well when is the time?
Soon.
Doris, I'll be back Doris. It's alright.
I'll come back.
What does the steak taste like again?
I had it once, but I can't remember...
If you can't remember then it's better to forget.
Alright then, what does it,
what does it smell like when it's cooking and that?
When it emanates around the place.
Curtis, is this it?
It's not it.
And I've heard this...
Curtis! Here!
Tim-bo. How's it hanging, buddy?
Give me a pound. Blow it up.
Hey, listen. I think I need that protein block.
How about I trade you? This one for that one?
No.
Nice bargaining, Curtis. Here.
Give me this one, I'll give you that.
Hey, relax, relax.
Come here, Timmy. Come here.
Come right...
I have an idea.
I'll give you this one and that one for that one.
What do you say?
No.
Go get him.
Timmy!
Timothy! Your mom's gonna give you
a damn good spanking!
Where the fuck he went?
Hey, come here. Come here. Give us it. Give us it.
You're alright, Jose. How you doing man?
Timmy! Work with me here!
Edgar, why did you let him get up there?
No, I didn't. He got up there by himself.
He's very nimble.
- He's five.
- He's a very nimble five year old.
Timmy! Sweetie, come down.
Come here.
What do you want for it?
In the whole wide train?
In the whole wide train.
The ball!
The ball? No, no, I'm sorry,
I can't do that. I can't do that.
Yes. I get the ball for a whole hour.
Done.
Curtis. Is it time?
Not yet, Tanya. Soon.
Red letter?
Yeah. It's the one we've been waiting for.
Our informant gave us the name.
N, A, M...
Nam Koong Min Soo.
He's a security expert.
He's in the Prison Section now.
Wait! You're joking, right?
- He's in prison?
- Hey, out of here.
No, I'm just saying, what kind of
chance do we have...
Edgar.
I just think that if this guys says that
he's such a great security expert
why can't he just break himself...
That's enough! Go!
Let's go, Tim. Come on. Let's go.
Edgar just wants to help, you know.
He thinks the world of you.
He shouldn't worship me the way he does.
I'm not who he thinks I am.
Few of us ever are.
Alright. We're here, Tail Section,
Quarantine Section, Prison Section.
Gate.
Four seconds when all three gates are opened at once.
We have four seconds to go through
three gates and bust Nam out.
Then Nam gets us the rest of the way?
Our fate depends on this man?
Yeah. If we can get him to cooperate,
he can take us all the way to the front of the train.
Very front section.
Yeah.
From here right to the front of the train.
Everything in one stroke.
We control the engine, we control the world.
Without that, we have nothing.
All past revolutions have failed because
they couldn't take the engine.
What are you saying?
This time, we take the engine.
Then what?
We kill him.
Wilford?
You should run the train now, not Wilford.
I'm a shadow of my former shadow.
My day was decades ago.
How old is Gilliam?
Shut up, Edgar.
And listen, I'm not saying that I want that
to happen, that's not what I'm saying.
What I mean is he will die someday.
And when that happens
you're gonna have to take over.
You're gonna have to run the train.
I'm not a leader.
I don't know. I think you'd be
pretty good if you ask me.
Hey, Edgar.
How far back can you remember?
- I don't know, like what?
- Your mother. You remember her?
I can remember her face, every once in a while...
But it's not clear.
Stay down everybody.
Everybody stay in your place.
Don't fucking look at me!
Keep down, keep down!
Medical Inspection. All the kids.
All the kids come with me. Just the kids.
All the kids.
Stay back there, ma'am. Just stay back there.
Stay back there. Stay.
Hello, what's this? We have one more.
Yup, come.
No, no, all need to go.
Come on.
No, no, we don't need to.
There's nothing wrong with him.
It's just a little medical check, sir. You just
stay back there. You just stay back there.
You! Go and check!
Don't move! Stay there!
Go, Timmy, go! Go!
That's her baby!
Andy!
Give me my son, you fucking bitch!
Andy! Andy!
How did you let him throw his shoe?
Timmy!
At this altitude, we need only 7 minutes.
Seven minutes allotted for your speech, sir.
This is so disappointing.
No no, we don't need all that.
We've only got seven minutes.
Passengers.
This is not a shoe. This is disorder.
This is size ten chaos.
This. See this. This is death.
In this locomotive we call home,
there is one thing
that between our warm hearts and the bitter cold.
Clothing? Shields? No! Order.
Order is the barrier that
holds back the frozen death.
We must all of us, on this train of life,
remain in our allotted station.
We must each of us occupy
our preordained particular position.
Would you wear a shoe on your head?
Of course you wouldn't wear a shoe on your head.
A shoe doesn't belong on your head.
A shoe belongs on your foot.
A hat belongs on your head.
I am a hat. You are a shoe.
I belong on the head. You belong on the foot.
Yes? So it is.
In the beginning, order
was prescribed by your ticket.
First class, economy, and free loaders like you.
Eternal order is prescribed by the Sacred Engine.
All things flow from the Sacred Engine.
All things in their place.
All passengers in their section.
All water flowing, all heat
rising pays homage
to the Sacred Engine. In its own
par-ti-cu-lar pre-ordained position.
So it is.
Now, as in the beginning, I belong to the front.
You belong to the tail.
When the foot seeks the place of the head,
a sacred line is crossed.
Know your place!
Keep your place!
Be a shoe!
We have 42 seconds left.
So we could go to a comment of Mr. Wilford,
the Divine Keeper of the Sacred Engine.
Sir? Mr. Wilford?
Are you there?
Are you there, sir?
Oh, it's breaking off.
Mr. Wilford is a very busy man.
So it is.
- Are we just gonna watch?
- Not now.
I'm not just gonna fucking sit here...
No, I'm alright.
Stop. Stop right there. Sit down!
Put that useless gun down, put it away.
Long time no see, Mr. Gilliam. It's a pleasure.
You look healthy.
He's fine.
Minister Mason, please deliver
a message to Mr. Wilford.
Certainly. What shall I say?
Tell him, he and I need to talk.
Well. You can talk to me.
Mr. Wilford has no reason to visit here...
Not here. At the front.
Your son will be a hero. Promise.
Or daughter, whatever it is.
I got it, I got it.
Your contribution has been duly noted. Thanks.
So sorry to interrupt you while you're praying.
What are you doin', man?
So sorry. Sumimasen.
Look. There's your Buddha back, thanks very much.
Move, move, move!
Stop fooling around!
I've got a better batch.
Stronger, fresh, uncut.
Wanna try some?
How many protein blocks for
ten rocks of uncut Kronole?
They don't have bullets.
Why do you say that?
You remember what Mason said?
She said, "Put down that useless gun."
She meant she wouldn't
give the order to shoot me.
No.
No, I think the guns are literally useless.
They used up all their bullets
four years ago, in the last revolt.
Bullets are extinct.
If you're wrong, we could be finished
before we even start.
I think we should be patient.
Wait for the next red letter.
Stay together. Left and right.
Not yet. Up, up. Now left, to the left.
Good, now forward.
Hello, Andrew! Andrew!
Wake up, rise and shine.
When you dream too much
of the sun, you forget the trees.
I believe this is your son.
I'm, I'm sorry, it's not very good.
It's not my best work, it's a little dark.
But if you look very deep into the eyes,
you can see a little bit of hope.
What about my boy?
You've got one of Timmy?
Oh yes, Tanya, I do. Easy, easy.
Come off this easy. You'll hurt yourself.
Here, there you go. Timmy.
Look at him.
Funny little smile.
Curtis, you gotta let me come with you.
No, Tanya. I'm sorry.
You will be if you don't let me come.
I'm going to the front and I'mma make that
bitch sorry she put her hands on my boy.
Make this one tighter.
You know I'm stronger than
all these skinny ass soldiers anyway.
Please!
Oh shit, what's going on?
They changed the schedule, boys. Move it back!
Now or never! They're coming now!
Don't panic! Stick with the plan.
Hide that! Hide it in your clothes!
Hide your weapons in your clothes!
Head check.
Line up.
Alright, sit down.
One, two, three, four...
What the fuck do we do?
I've had enough of this protein block bullshit!
Yeah, this is bullshit!
We're fucking hungry, man!
I want chicken!
We're not gonna sit down for this shite!
We want chicken! Chicken!
It's okay.
You want him fucking dead? Is that it?
Be quiet!
Still going for it, are we?
Come on, let's go! Let's do it.
The rifles.
No, we can overwhelm them.
We easily outnumber their bullets.
This is it.
Curtis, come on. We're out of time.
You gotta do it now.
They've got no bullets!
I'm fine, Grey. You go now!
"Nam Koong Min Soo. Kronole Addict."
That explains a lot, doesn't it?
Hurry up, Edgar.
Hurry up?
So sorry for keeping you all waiting.
Obviously I work here.
Open it.
Here we go!
Hey, Kronole head!
So, this is Kronole?
I heard it's pretty big in the front section.
Careful, that's how these guys hallucinate.
It's industrial waste.
And it's highly flammable.
Are you Nam Koong Min Soo? Security specialist?
Did you design all the door locks
and security systems on the train?
Look at him man, he's gone. Look at his eyes.
He's fried his brain with that fucking shite.
Are you Nam?
Nam, are you listening?
Yes, I'm listening, fuck.
It's not "Nem", it's "Nam".
Namgoong Minsoo, shit.
Surname is Namgoong,
first name is Minsoo, asshole.
Unknown words found.
Please try again with correct vocabulary.
We need your help.
For what?
We're going to the front and
we need you to open up the gates.
What if I say no?
Uncut. Straight from the barrel.
Every door you open, you get one lump of Kronole.
Jesus! Marlboro Light?
I can't believe it. Cigarettes have been
extinct for more than 10 years now.
Do you want some, asshole?
I bet you fuckhead never smoked one before.
I'm gonna make this real simple for you.
You help us, you get your drug.
If not, we put you back where we found you.
What'll it be, asshole?
Chan.
Chan. Get outta here. Just get out.
Hey, that's enough.
Put him back in the fucking drawer!
Get up.
My Daughter, Yona.
If I go, she goes too.
So, you're coming with us?
One gate, 2 lumps of Kronole.
She's an addict, too?
Nobody there.
Kronole.
Look at all these beds. Where is everybody?
Looks like they left in a hurry.
There's some food on the table.
This can't be a window, can it?
Still cold.
Dead. All dead.
Alright! Let's go everyone!
Stay focus. We didn't come here for this.
Alright! You heard the man. Let's go! Move!
Nem! Nam!
Kronole.
How did you know there was nobody there?
He's running.
Paul?
Paul!
What the hell is he doing, man? Paul!
He looks so different.
Yeah, just a second. Used to be automatic.
But parts went extinct.
He's not the Paul I remember.
No. Paul! It's Curtis!
Ain't comin' back... so now I got to do it.
Manually!
So that's how it's made. Still hot.
Look at them all! Man, you did some nice work!
That's right, man! There's your food!
There's your protein blocks!
Is this why they took you? To make this garbage?
Paul?
You've been alone this whole time?
Alone! In the zone!
We're going to the front. Come with us!
Oh, right! You're going to the front? Yeah, man!
But, no way man. My place is here. Alright?
Here? Making this crap? Why?
You can't draw this.
Okay.
All this time, we've been eating this shit?
Hey, I eat them too, you know.
Every single day.
Where did you get this?
Have you been the one writing these?
I don't write 'em.
Why do you have this? Who gave this to you?
They just leave 'em for me ,man. I put them
in the protein blocks. I send them on. That's it!
The Water Supply Section?
Yeah. It's just a few cars up. It's where
the water's cleansed and recycled.
It's one of the most
crucial sections in the train.
If we take it, we have the upper hand?
We don't even have to
go to the very front.
We control the water, we control the negotiation.
Uh, hi, hi, excuse me. Sorry to bother you there.
Can I get you a glass of water or
something to speed this up?
Listen! Would you get on with it, man?
You're keeping us all fucking waiting!
Am I?
Yeah, you are.
Although you've been
fucking smelling that flammable shite,
that time is probably a distant
fucking concept for you, isn't it?
Of course, I'm only doing this for Kronole.
Here we go again, Kronole this, Kronole that.
Christ almighty, man. Do some fucking work!
You're the one who gives it to me.
Are you a bit thick? That's what you ask for
each time you open a gate!
Of course, I'm only doing this for Kronole.
Yona. It's Yona, right?
How old are you?
Seventeen.
Seventeen. You're a train baby, then?
How 'bout you?
Seventeen years on Earth.
Seventeen years in the Tail Section.
Earth? What was it like?
I don't remember.
Why?
I don't want to remember anything
before I met Gilliam.
Yona.
Are you clairvoyant?
Clairvoyant? What's that?
Well, you always seem to know what's behind the gates.
Do you see things in your mind?
Don't open it.
What?
Lock the gate!
Be careful.
Yeah, you too.
Team 2 move!
Move forward!
Passing Yekaterina Bridge!
We're at the bridge, guys!
Ten. Nine.
Eight. Seven. Six.
Five. Four.
Three. Two. One.
Happy New Year!
Fucking hate getting old, I fucking hate it.
Wilford! Banzai! Banzai!
Everybody down!
Hang on!
Impact!
Not yet! A second one!
Stay down!
Nam, what are you doing man? What are you doing?
He's high as a fucking kite.
Here it comes.
Safe passage.
Hey, watch it! Watch out!
Come on!
One, two, three. One, two.
Happy Yekaterina Bridge, you filthy ingrates!
You people, who if not for the benevolent Wilford,
would have frozen solid 18 years ago today!
You people...
Who have sucked on the generous titty of Wilford
ever since, for food and shelter!
And now, in front of
our hallowed water supply section, no less!
You repay his kindness with
violent hooliganism?
You scum.
Precisely 74% of you shall die.
My friend, you suffer from
the misplaced optimism of the doomed.
This is going to be good.
What? What did you say?
He said you guys are fucked.
You stupid Tail Sectioners.
There's a tunnel right after Yekaterina Bridge.
A tunnel?
Mm-hmm, a fucking long one!
Let's go.
Everybody back!
Chan. Get outta here. Just get out.
Chan! We need fire!
Chan! Bring the fire!
Tell them in the back
we need to get the lights up here!
Chan has the matches!
Got you, motherfucker!
Officer Fuyu! What are you doing?
Don't look at me, you dozy bugger!
Look there!
Put me down! Stop squeezing my legs!
Surrender!
Surrender! Surrender!
He will kill me if we don't surrender!
Shit...
Curtis!
Stop! Stop everybody!
Drop your weapon.
Stop!
Everybody stop!
Do what he says, for crying out loud.
Drop your weapons!
Don't look.
Survivors! Wash yourselves!
The Water Supply Section.
Wash away the blood.
Have you seen these kids?
I don't know anything about...
Look! Where are they, you bitch?
I don't know. I don't know.
It's not me. It's not me.
Tell us or I'll cut your fucking arm off.
Even shorter than mine, you bastard!
Wilford... Wilford knows.
Wil... Wilford... Wilford likes kids.
He does. That's why he sends that
yellow one Claude to get them for him...
It... it's Wilford you want, not me.
Wilford likes kids?
All he cares about is his wretched engine!
The Engine is Sacred.
And Wilford is Divine.
Wilford is merciful.
Call him. See if he'll come save you.
Yes.
Wilford The Merciful. Call him.
He won't come here. He won't leave his Engine.
We're going to rip you into little pieces.
He still won't come?
Well, we control the water.
We turn that off, he'll have to come.
Turn off the water?
Well, you'll only be condemning your own people.
The water comes from the front.
The nose of the train breaks up the snow
and ice and turns it into water.
It's like an elephant's trunk. The water
comes in the mouth, not in the bum.
Curtis!
Yes. Wilford knows you well, Mr. Curtis Everett.
He's been watching you.
And we know you won't harm your own people.
Too bad you couldn't save
your second in command.
- What was his name, Edgar?
- Shut the fuck up!
Curtis! Curtis! I can help you!
You can fucking die is what you can do.
No, I can help you! I swear it!
Listen, listen to me!
Wilford won't come here! He's not coming!
You've got to go to him!
And I can take you. I know the train.
I can guarantee you safe passage.
Why the fuck would I trust you?
Because I want to live.
So you'd sell out Wilford The Benevolent?
If I take you to the front,
you have to kill him.
I'll get you close enough.
You kill him and let me live.
Curtis?
You're still determined to push ahead?
Of course. We're not even halfway.
You've already gone further than anyone else.
Further than MacGregor four years ago.
Ten cars, twenty cars, it doesn't matter
unless we make it to the engine.
They'll just regroup and attack us again.
We gotta pull them out by the roots.
But so many have been killed.
We've lost so many.
I know.
Have you seen our men? They are exhausted.
I told them to wash themselves,
so that I could assess the damage.
Let me go ahead.
I've got Mason now.
I can move a lot faster.
You stay here with the wounded.
Guard the prisoners.
When we take the engine,
I'll call for you to lead us.
Stop it, Curtis. Why are you doing that?
You know very well that you're already our leader.
You have to accept that now.
How can I lead if I have two good arms?
It's faded a lot.
Better to have both arms.
Can't do a lot with one, you know.
Especially when you hold a woman.
It's much better to have two arms, wouldn't you agree?
When you get to the narrow bridge,
big gate with the W on it.
Wilford's behind that.
Don't let Wilford talk.
Cut out his tongue.
Okay, let's all get in there, squeeze in!
Perfect, perfect! The hat becomes you well.
Now, Grey... You must go with Curtis.
Oops, forgot somebody.
Kronole.
Don't mind me. Back to work,
everyone, back to work.
Minister.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Please don't eat it, don't eat it.
No, no, no, no, they're very friendly.
They won't bite.
Well, they might bite the tomato, but...
Can I eat this?
Train baby like you wouldn't know.
I used to walk on this every day.
Under the snow this is everywhere.
Earth.
What's this?
It's moving.
Over there.
What's that?
Hey.
Do any of you feel like sushi?
Hell yeah, line that shit up.
Right?
You people are very lucky.
This is only served twice in a year,
in January and July.
Why? Not enough fish?
Oh, "enough" is not the criterion.
Balance.
You see, this aquarium is
a closed ecological system.
The number of individual units must be
very closely, precisely controlled
in order to maintain
the proper sustainable balance.
No.
You eat this.
You know what that's made of?
Dig in.
Curtis, my friend, do you think we might dispense
with the restraints for this next Section?
I am not your friend and why would I?
For the sake of the young? Education?
Quiet! Quiet!
Good morning, children.
I am pleased to present guests from the Tail Section.
Yes and what do we say to
Tail Section guests, children?
Good morning, Tail Section guests.
Timmy! Timmy!
Andy! Andy! Andrew...
This little boy. His name is Timmy.
This is my son. Please, take a
good look at the picture!
I saw them!
- When?
- Where?
Came through there, went through there.
Is that all, boy?
Yes.
Were they crying?
No, but they looked like they wanted to.
I heard all Tail Sectioners were lazy dogs
who slept all day in their own shit.
No, they're very nice!
And very just and merciful. So it is.
Minister Mason, we were
just about to show a video.
Very good!
Wilford!
From a very young age, Mr. Wilford's
love of locomotives was apparent.
When I grow up, I want to
live in a train. Forever!
Forever!
His early dreams were realized
when he founded his transportation empire
the Wilford Industries.
But his greatest dream was to
construct a luxury locomotive cruise line.
Connecting railways of
the entire world into one!
A circular railway that extends for 438,000 kilometers
and completes one circle every year.
Impervious to the extreme cold of the Arctic
and the scorching heat of the African desert.
Wilford's miracle train is self-sustaining
and possesses the most sophisticated designs
and advanced technology known--
As hard as it is to believe,
people in the Old World made fun of Mr. Wilford.
They criticized him for over-engineering
and over-equipping this wonderful train.
But Wilford knew something they did not.
And what was that?
Old World people were frigging morons
who got turned into popsicles!
Well, sort of.
Mr. Wilford knew that
CW-7 would freeze the world.
So what did the prophetic Mr. Wilford invent to
protect the chosen from that calamity?
The Engine!
Rumble, rumble, rattle, rattle.
It will never die!
♪ What happens if the engine stops? ♪
♪ We all freeze and die ♪
♪ But will it stop, oh, will it stop? ♪
♪ No! No! ♪
♪ Can you tell us why? ♪
♪ The engine is eternal ♪
♪ Yes! ♪
♪ The engine is forever ♪
♪ Rumble, rumble, rattle, rattle! ♪
♪ Who is the reason why? ♪
♪ Wilford, yeah! ♪
Wilford! Wilford! Hip hooray!
I love that one, such a tonic.
Oh, it's time, children!
Come this way! Don't trip now!
Don't push! There's plenty of room.
Who can tell me what's coming up?
The Frozen Seven!
Pay attention. This tableau
will surely be on the exam!
Fifteen years ago, in the third year of
the train, seven passengers tried
to stop Wilford's Miracle Train and go outside!
And what do we call this event, Magdalena?
The Revolt of the Seven.
Very good. Long before you were born.
Of course, they failed to stop the train.
Instead, they jumped out of the running train.
Here they come now.
You look too.
Why?
There they are. That's how far they made it.
That person in the front...
...was a cleaning lady from the front section.
She was an Inuit. You know, Eskimo.
She taught me about every type of snow and ice.
She believed we could survive outside the train.
If we ever go outside the train?
We'd all freeze and die!
If the engine stops running?
We'd all die!
And who takes care of the Sacred Engine?
Sir Wilford!
Children! It's the New Year eggs from Mr. Wilford!
Touch them, they are still warm.
These eggs are boiled using water
heated by the Sacred Engine itself.
As a special treat, we have playing for us,
the world-renowned first chair violinist of
the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
Mr. Gerald McInster!
Is that really Gerald? He looks damn great!
No, thank you very much.
Let's go, Curtis.
Happy New Year!
I thought the chicken was extinct.
There are actually many things on board
were rumored to be extinct.
Such as?
This.
Andrew! No!
It wasn't me! It wasn't me!
No.
Curtis!
You have to lead us.
Curtis, my friend.
We understand each other.
Listen to my words! It wasn't me!
We go forward.
Open!
Hurry!
It's Mason.
Shit. Check her pulse.
Hey, hey, fire regulation...
God, that does not look good.
He's coming.
Got the master key, right?
Wait, don't shoot. Please don't shoot.
You just killed a Front Section Passenger! I'm...
I didn't see a thing.
Where are you going? Wait, just wait a minute!
Can't we talk about it just for one second...
You son of a bitch!
Close the door.
Tanya.
Oh...
My Timmy.
We're gonna find him. I promise.
I know.
Thank you.
You grab some too.
Hey, turn around, motherfucker!
You got my Kronole!
I want that shit!
I'm coming after you, man!
I want my Kronole back!
That's my Kronole, motherfucker!
I swear, man! I'm gonna kill you,
you spaced-out fuck!
Open the door.
Come on, Kronole.
Kronole? You want Kronole?
Here. Take it.
Open it. Open the gate!
You're crazy.
Fucking obsessed with gates.
Here, have a smoke.
You should be grateful.
The world's last cigarette, you tail section dick.
You ever been to the Tail Section?
Do you have any idea what went on
back there? When we boarded?
It was chaos.
Yeah, we didn't freeze to death
but we didn't have time to be thankful.
Wilford's soldiers came and they took everything.
A thousand people in an iron box.
No food, no water.
After a month, we ate the weak.
Do you know what I hate about myself?
I know what people taste like.
I know that babies taste best.
There was a woman. She was hiding with her baby.
Then some men with knives came.
They killed her and they took her baby.
And then, an old man...
No relation, just an old man.
Stepped forward and he said, "Give me the knife."
And everyone thought he'd kill the baby himself.
But he took the knife, and he cut off his arm.
And he said, "Eat this. If you're so hungry,
eat this. Just leave the baby."
I have never seen anything like that.
And the men put down their knives.
Probably guessed who that old man was.
That baby was Edgar.
And I was the man with the knife.
I killed Edgar's mother.
And then one by one, other people in the
Tail Section started cutting off arms and legs and...
...offering them.
It was like a miracle.
And I wanted to.
I tried. I just...
A month later, Wilford's soldiers
brought those protein blocks.
We've been eating that shit ever since.
Eighteen years I've hated Wilford.
Eighteen years I've waited for this moment.
And now I'm here.
Open the gate.
Please.
Thanks for your story, Curtis.
But I don't want to open the gate.
You know what I really want?
I want to open the gate.
Not this gate.
But that one.
The gate to the outside world.
It's been frozen shut for eighteen years.
You might take it as a wall.
But it's a fucking gate.
Let's open it and just get the hell out.
And freeze to death? What are you, fucking crazy?
What if we don't?
What if we could survive outside?
Remember the Yekaterina Bridge?
When you were being chopped up.
There's something I look at every New Year.
Under the snow is a crashed airplane.
Ten years ago, I could barely see the tail.
Now I can see its body and its wings.
There's less ice and snow.
In other words, it's melting.
The type of snow that's about to melt.
A little push and it all falls down.
Recently...
...you know what I saw?
Outside the window, there was...
Nevermind. I don't have to tell you this.
You gotta take it easy on that Kronole.
Snorting that flammable
shit's gonna fry your brain.
That's exactly right.
Kronole is originally...
...an industrial waste, highly flammable.
When it's lit, boom!
Simply put, it's a fucking bomb!
I didn't stock up on it for years just to get high.
It's to blow up this gate.
Give me the matches!
What the fuck are you doing?
Give it to me.
Take that off the door.
Curtis Everett.
I've been asked to extend a formal invitation from
Mr. Wilford to join him for dinner.
After you.
Curtis! Is that you?
Curtis, dear boy. Come in.
Let's take a look at you.
You hungry? You did a man's
work coming all this way.
Please sit down.
You are the first human being to have walked
the total length of this train. Tail to Engine.
Did you know that? Well done. Bravo.
None of your people have ever been here.
To the engine.
I've never been to the Tail Section.
Why not? Too dirty for you?
Don't want to rub against
the vermin of the Tail Section?
Do you think my station is
without its own drawbacks?
It's noisy. And it's lonely.
Right.
Steaks. Plenty of room.
This whore to bring you anything you want.
Curtis, everyone has their preordained position.
And everyone is in their place except you.
That's what people in the best place
say to people in the worst place.
There's not a soul on this train
who wouldn't trade places with you.
Would you trade places with me?
Fuck you.
Curtis, dear boy, the fact is we are
all stuck inside this blasted train.
We are all prisoners in this hunk of metal.
Medium rare?
And this train is a closed ecosystem.
We must always strive for balance.
The air, the water, the food supply,
the population...
...must be always kept in balance.
For optimum balance,
however, there have been times
when more radical solutions were required.
When the population needed to
be reduced rather drastically.
We don't have time for true natural selection.
We would all be hideously overcrowded
and starved waiting for that.
The next best solution is to have individual
units kill off other individual units.
From time to time, we've had to
stir the pot so to speak.
The Revolt of the Seven.
The MacGregor Riots.
The Great Curtis Revolution!
A blockbuster production with
a devilishly unpredictable plot!
Who could have predicted your counterattack
with the torch in the Yekaterina Tunnel?
Pure genius. That wasn't what
Gilliam and I had in our plan.
What?
Don't tell me you didn't know.
Gilliam and I. Our plan.
Gilliam?
Gilliam.
The front and the tail
are supposed to work together.
He was more than a partner, really.
He was my friend.
Bullshit.
I don't believe you.
Our original agreement was for
the insurgency to end at the Yekaterina Tunnel.
And all the survivors would go back to
the Tail Section to enjoy much more space.
You're a fucking liar.
Gilliam would never do that.
It all worked out in the end.
Your counterattack actually made
the insurgency ten times more exciting.
Unfortunately, the front suffered
more losses than anticipated,
and Gilliam had to pay the price.
Ironic, isn't it?
How people dramatically cross that
thin barrier between life and death?
Now, there is just one last thing for us to do.
Tally up the numbers.
Hello, Wilford. It's me.
I'm at Gilliam's place.
Hold on.
Is it still the same number?
Yes, it still stands at 74 percent.
Okay. Carry on.
Wait.
Spare eighteen to celebrate our 18th year.
It's a... An excellent idea. Yes.
Your people.
God damn it, Claude. Mind the Engine!
She's getting sensitive recently.
Sit down and mind your table manners.
Just relax.
Calm down.
Boy, now I can see what Gilliam meant.
He told me you were brilliant and clever,
but always so tense.
When's the last time you got laid?
Like Gilliam said, holding a woman
is much better with two arms.
I'll miss Gilliam.
I'll miss our late night phone chats.
He could go on for hours,
all with only one arm!
What's with that face? What's the matter?
You look like a crazy person. As if there
aren't enough crazies on this train!
Blood!
Are you okay?
What happened?
Get down!
Yona.
Open that gate and get the Kronole!
See those wires inside?
Shit, tons of 'em...
Kill! You punk!
I believe it is easier for someone to survive on
this train if they have some level of insanity.
I mean as Gilliam well understood,
we need to maintain a proper
balance of anxiety and fear,
chaos and horror in order
to keep life going.
If we don't have that, we need to invent it.
In that sense,
the Great Curtis Revolution
you invented was truly a masterpiece.
Yona!
Red goes into 8!
No, 7!
Come with me, Curtis.
Something I want to show you.
You deserve it.
Come on.
She's waking up now.
Cozy, yes? Peaceful.
You are now in her heart.
I've devoted my entire life to this.
The Eternal Engine.
It is eternity itself.
Have you ever been alone on this train?
When was the last time you were alone?
You can't remember, can you?
So please do, take your time.
I just wrote it.
It's for you, Curtis.
Here.
I am old.
I want you to take my station.
It's what you always wanted.
It's what Gilliam wanted too.
You must tend the Engine, keep her humming.
Look, Curtis. Beyond the gate.
Section after section precisely
where they've always been and
where they'll always be all adding up to what?
The train.
And now, the perfectly
correct number of human beings
all in their proper places all adding up to what?
Humanity.
The train is the world, we the humanity.
And now you have the sacred responsibility
to lead all of humanity.
Without you, Curtis, humanity will cease to exist.
You've seen what people do without leadership.
They devour one another.
Yona, the Kronole!
Yona, stop!
No bullet?
Put the Kronole on the gate.
Look at them.
That's how people are.
You know. You've seen this.
You've been this.
Ridiculous, pathetic, aren't they?
You can save them from themselves.
This is what Gilliam saved you for.
Curtis.
This is your destiny.
It's ready!
Curtis has the match!
Curtis!
The match!
The space only allows for a very small person.
Young children under five.
The Engine lasts forever
but not so all of its parts.
That piece of equipment went extinct recently.
We needed a replacement.
Thank goodness the Tail Section
manufactures a steady supply of kids.
So we can keep going manually.
You fucking bastard!
Yona.
Take the fire.
Only one left!
Andy? Is that you?
Andy! You remember me?
Andy, stop! Listen to me!
Don't go up those stairs! Listen!
Andy!
Come here! Come over here!
Andy, listen to me!
Get out of there!
God damn it, Andy, listen to me!
Oh Curtis, don't be so melodramatic.
You know everyone has
their own preordained position.
Nice.
Dad! Dad!
Curtis. Curtis.
Just stay there!